const questions: Array<QuestionType> = [
  {
    question: 'אמן',
    answers: ['hij vertrouwde', 'hij geloofde'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'אָרַר',
    answers: ['hij vervloekte'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'גּוֹאֵל',
    answers: ['losser', 'vrijkoper'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'גָּלָה',
    answers: ['hij legde bloot', 'hij openbaarde', 'hij verdween', 'hij ging in ballingschap'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'גָּמָל',
    answers: ['kameel'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'יוֹשֵׁב',
    answers: ['inwoner'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'יוֹצֵר',
    answers: ['pottenbakker'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'יָצַר',
    answers: ['hij kneedde', 'hij vormde'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'מוֹשִׁיעַ',
    answers: ['Heiland', 'Verlosser', 'Redder'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'מַלְאָךְ',
    answers: ['bode', 'boodschapper', 'engel'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'נָגַע',
    answers: ['hij raakte', 'hij raakte aan', 'hij trof'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'נָגַשׁ',
    answers: ['hij naderde', 'hij trad aan'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'נָהָר',
    answers: ['stroom', 'zee', 'rivier'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'סוֹפֵר',
    answers: ['schrijver'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'פָּדָה',
    answers: ['hij kocht vrij', 'hij verloste'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'פָּשַׁע',
    answers: ['hij vergreep zich', 'hij schond regels', 'hij zondigde', 'hij overtrad', 'hij overtreedde'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'רוֹאֶה',
    answers: ['ziener', 'profeet'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'רוֹעֶה',
    answers: ['herder'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'רָעָה',
    answers: ['hij weidde', 'hij liet grazen'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'שַׂר',
    answers: ['overste', 'hoge ambtenaar', 'notabele', 'opziener', 'hoofd', 'vorst', 'aanvoerder', 'prins'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'שָׁאַר',
    answers: ['hij bleef over', 'hij bleef achter', 'hij overleefde'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'שׁוֹפֵט',
    answers: ['rechter', 'richter'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'שָׁקָה',
    answers: ['hij gaf te drinken', 'hij drenkte'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  },
  {
    question: 'תּוֹעֵבָה',
    answers: ['gruwel', 'wat afschuw wekt'],
    type: 'woordenschat'
  }
]
const lesson19Vocabulary: LessonType = {
  id: 'lesson19-vocabulary',
  name: 'Les 19 – Woordenschat',
  type: 'woordenschat',
  active: false,
  questions
}
export default lesson19Vocabulary
